Shivam Kumar Singh

■ shivam.nitrkl21@gmail.com 🛘 +918218758830 📠 linkedin.com/in/shivam14me51 🕳 https://shivam-kr-singh.github.io/

SUMMARY

As a UI/UX designer with 2 years of experience, I am passionate about creating intuitive and visually appealing designs that enhance user experience. I have a strong background in creating wireframes, prototyping, and designing interfaces for web and mobile applications. During my time at current organization, I successfully completed the project of various domains like B2B, SaaS, Analytics, Education and Ed-Tech etc.

I believe that design is not just about aesthetics, but also about creating solutions that solve real-world problems. I always start by understanding the user's needs and behaviors, and then design interfaces that are easy to use and visually appealing.

If you're looking for a UI/UX designer who is passionate about creating beautiful and intuitive designs, please feel free to reach out to me. I would love to hear from you!

EXPERIENCE

UX & UI Designer

Think Design Collaborative

July 2021 - Present, Bangalore

As a UI/UX Designer, I am responsible for designing products that offer a seamless customer/user experience. This involves conducting user research and analysis, wireframing, usability testing, prototyping, and creating mockups. I collaborate closely with stakeholders and the marketing team to understand the business and developers to ensure the successful development of apps and websites. In addition to my UI/UX Design responsibilities, I also work as a Data Designer. I analyze data and develop dashboards on BI tools like Tableau, Google Data Studio, Power BI, and Google Sheets. I have experience working in various domains such as B2B, SAAS, Analytics, E-Commerce, Ed-Tech, and BFSI.

Placement Coordinator

National Institute of Technology Rourkela

May 2020 - July 2021, May 2020 - Jul 2021 · 1 yr 3 mos

As a Placement Coordinator, my responsibility is to interface with companies visiting NIT Rourkela for campus recruitment. I am responsible for strategic decision-making, scheduling, logistics, hospitality, and managing students. To be successful in this role, I need to have strong communication, negotiation, and project management skills. Additionally, I need to leverage technology and data analytics tools to streamline the recruitment process and improve outcomes.

Data Analyst Intern

Edulyt India

May 2020 - June 2020, Delhi, India · Remote

As a Data Analyst Intern, my main responsibility is to assist the Data Analyst in analyzing large datasets, cleaning and manipulating data, and creating reports and presentations for stakeholders. I need to be proficient in data analysis techniques and data visualization tools, as well as SQL. Attention to detail, strong analytical skills, and the ability to work collaboratively are essential in this role. This internship will provide me with valuable experience in data analysis and help me develop highly sought–after skills.

EDUCATION

M.Tech, Industrial Design

National Institute of Technology Rourkela · 2021 · 9.13

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Mechanical Engineering

Mahatma Jyotiba Phule Rohilkhand Úniversity • 2018 • 7.8

CERTIFICATIONS

Communicate your ideas through storytelling and design

Google Digital Garage · 2023

Cutshort Certified HTML/CSS - Basic

Cutshort · 2022

SKILLS

Industry Knowledge: UI, Visual Design, User Interface Design, Design Systems, Customer Journeys, Customer Experience Design, User-centered Design, Wireframing, Information Architecture, User Experience Design (UED), Web Design, Data Analytics, User Experience (UX), Data Visualization

Tools & Technologies: Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Excel, Infogram Data Visualization, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), InVision, Prototyping, HTML, Tableau, Adobe Creative Suite, Figma (Software), Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, CATIA

Interpersonal Skills: Management, Analytical Skills, Team Management, Leadership, Strategic Planning, Communication, Teamwork

Languages: CSS, HTML